IAN **PARAVENTI**

CAREER FOCUS: FRONTEND DEVELOPER

Recent bachelor's degree recipient with a background in web design and development. Over 5 years of experience working on personal websites and for others, using a variety of tools. A firm believer in the mobile-first approach and creating web accessible sites for everyone.

EDUCATION

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE IN INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY

Oakland University September 2017 – May 2020

GENERAL EDUCATION

Macomb Community College August 2015 – May 2017

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming Languages/Frameworks: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Node, PHP, SQL, WordPress, Bootstrap

Software Applications:

Visual Studio Code, Git, Jira Service Desk, Adobe Photoshop

EXPERIENCE

TECHNOLOGY ADMIN SPECIALIST/WEB DEVELOPER | AUTO CREDIT EXPRESS

December 2019 - November 2020

- Maintained existing websites utilizing PHP, MySQL, JavaScript, and HTML.
- Performed validation of completed sites including the debugging and testing of code.
- Provided PC support, diagnosing, troubleshooting, and resolving client issues with hardware maintenance, installations, and upgrades.
- Maintained multiple servers running on Windows Server and Linux.

INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY INTERN | JVIS

December 2016 - January 2017

- Worked the Help Desk providing hardware/software installations, upgrades, repairs, and maintenance.
- Installed, repaired, and upgraded Windows desktop and Windows notebook computers.
- Prepared equipment for employee use, performed or ensured proper installation of services, operating systems, or appropriate software.

PROJECTS - VIEW MORE AT IANPARA.COM

"BLOGPAD" CUSTOM WORDPRESS THEME

Summary: Took a Figma design and developed it into a functional site. Then converted that into a WordPress site creating a custom theme and plugins.

Tools Used: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, PHP, WordPress

VENTI WEB DESIGN & DEVELOPMENT

Summary: Created a website to showcase my web development skills and promote my freelance business. Using PHP and a MySQL database I created my own CMS for publishing blogs and templating pages. Better understood SEO and implementing accessibility best practices.

Tools Used: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP, MySQL

CROWDFUNDING PRODUCT PAGE

Summary: A challenge to build out a crowdfunding product page and get it looking as close to a design given as possible. Requirements included: View the optimal layout depending on their device's screen size, see hover states for interactive elements, select which pledge to make, and see an updated pledged progress bar.

Tools Used: HTML, CSS, JavaScript